[
  {
    "questionNumber": 1,
    "questionText": "Which of the following is a derived unit?",
    "question_images": [],
    "option_with_images_": [
      "(a) mass",
      "(b) time",
      "(c) area",
      "(d) length"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "C"
  },
  {
    "questionNumber": 2,
    "questionText": "Which of the following is correct?",
    "question_images": [],
    "option_with_images_": [
      "(a) 1L = 1cc",
      "(b) 1L = 10 cc",
      "(c) 1L = 100 cc",
      "(d) 1L = 1000 cc"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "D"
  },
  {
    "questionNumber": 3,
    "questionText": "SI unit of density is",
    "question_images": [],
    "option_with_images_": [
      "(a) kg / m²",
      "(b) kg / m³",
      "(c) kg / m",
      "(d) g / m³"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "B"
  },
  {
    "questionNumber": 4,
    "questionText": "Two spheres have equal mass and volume in the ratio 2: 1. The ratio of their density is",
    "question_images": [],
    "option_with_images_": [
      "(a) 1: 2",
      "(b) 2: 1",
      "(c) 4: 1",
      "(d) 1: 4"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "B"
  },
  {
    "questionNumber": 5,
    "questionText": "Light year is the unit of",
    "question_images": [],
    "option_with_images_": [
      "(a) Distance",
      "(b) time",
      "(c) density",
      "(d) both length and time"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "A"
  },
  {
    "questionNumber": 6,
    "questionText": "Which of the following is a fundamental quantity?",
    "question_images": [],
    "option_with_images_": [
      "(a) Speed",
      "(b) Kilogram per cubic metre",
      "(c) Luminous intensity"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "C"
  },
  {
    "questionNumber": 7,
    "questionText": "Which of the following is the derived quantity?",
    "question_images": [],
    "option_with_images_": [
      "(a) Ampere",
      "(b) Luminous intensity",
      "(c) Speed"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "A"
  },
  {
    "questionNumber": 8,
    "questionText": "Iron has a higher density compared to the __________.",
    "question_images": [],
    "option_with_images_": [
      "(a) Gold",
      "(b) Water",
      "(c) Silver"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "B"
  },
  {
    "questionNumber": 9,
    "questionText": "Materials with a lower density are known as __________ material.",
    "question_images": [],
    "option_with_images_": [
      "(a) Gaseous",
      "(b) Rarer",
      "(c) Solid"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "A"
  },
  {
    "questionNumber": 10,
    "questionText": "Pick the odd one out:",
    "question_images": [],
    "option_with_images_": [
      "(a) Gram",
      "(b) Kilolitre",
      "(c) Astronomical units",
      "(d) Centimetre"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "C"
  },
  {
    "questionNumber": 11,
    "questionText": "Which one is correct of the following options?",
    "question_images": [],
    "option_with_images_": [
      "(a) nanomètre > kilomètre",
      "(b) gallon < centilitre < litre",
      "(c) kilolitre > gallon > centilitre",
      "(d) millilitre < centilitre < kilolitre"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "C"
  },
  {
    "questionNumber": 12,
    "questionText": "The value of one light year is,",
    "question_images": [],
    "option_with_images_": [
      "(a) 9.46 ×10^12 m",
      "(b) 9.46 ×10^18 m",
      "(c) 9.46 ×10^15 m",
      "(d) 9.40 ×10^15 m"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "A"
  },
  {
    "questionNumber": 13,
    "questionText": "The formula for density (D) is given as",
    "question_images": [],
    "option_with_images_": [
      "Density =Mass / Area",
      "(b) Density =Volume / Mass",
      "(c) Density =Mass / Volume"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "C"
  },
  {
    "questionNumber": 14,
    "questionText": "A circular disc has a radius of 10 cm . Find the area of the disc in m² ( Use π = 3.14).",
    "question_images": [],
    "option_with_images_": [
      "(a) 0.0314 m²",
      "(b) 0.314 m²",
      "(c) 0.00314 m²",
      "(d) 31.4 m²"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "A"
  },
  {
    "questionNumber": 15,
    "questionText": "The mass of sphere is given as",
    "question_images": [],
    "option_with_images_": [
      "(a) Mass = Volume x Density",
      "(b) Mass = Density x Area",
      "(c) Mass = Density x Volume"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "A"
  },
  {
    "questionNumber": 16,
    "questionText": "The space occupied by a body is its",
    "question_images": [],
    "option_with_images_": [
      "(a) Area",
      "(b) Volume",
      "(c) Perimeter",
      "(d) Density"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "B"
  },
  {
    "questionNumber": 17,
    "questionText": "The average distance between the earth and the sun.",
    "question_images": [],
    "option_with_images_": [
      "(a) 150 million kilometers",
      "(b) 15 million kilometers",
      "(c) 1.5 billion kilometers",
      "(d) 1500 million kilometers"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "A"
  },
  {
    "questionNumber": 18,
    "questionText": "The water displacement method was found by",
    "question_images": [],
    "option_with_images_": [
      "(a) Albert Einstein",
      "(b) Isaac Newton",
      "(c) Archimedes",
      "(d) Galileo Galilei"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "C"
  },
  {
    "questionNumber": 19,
    "questionText": "The nearest star to our solar system",
    "question_images": [],
    "option_with_images_": [
      "(a) Rigel",
      "(b) Alpha Centauri",
      "(c) Sirius",
      "(d) Proxima Centauri"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "D"
  },
  {
    "questionNumber": 20,
    "questionText": "The value of one light-year can be calculated by multiplying",
    "question_images": [],
    "option_with_images_": [
      "(a) Speed of light × Time",
      "(b) Distance x Speed",
      "(c) Time x Distance"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "A"
  }
]